Guide to the McGee Family Papers, 1857-2016 and undated RL.10042
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Materials and Publications, 1857-2010 and undated, 13 boxes
  - Books from the library of John S. and Doris McGee
    - Bible, New Testament, 1978 (Box 14)
    - Bible, King James Version, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Bible, Good News, 1976 (Box 15)
    - The Nugget, 1935 (Box 15)
    - Laurel, 1936 (Box 15)
    - Laurel, 1940 (Box 15)
    - I Dare You, by W. Danforth, 1938 (Box 15)
    - God Moving in My Behalf, by Ella Pierce, undated (Box 15)
    - A Story to Tell, by Carlton Whirley, 1988 (Box 16)
    - Round Up, 1941 (Box 16)
    - Mars Hill 50th Reunion, 1939-1989 (Box 16)
    - Bragtown 50th Reunion, 1935-1985 (Box 16)
    - Nigerian "MK" Facebook comments, 2015 (Box 35)
  - Books from the library of John David McGee
    Includes books on the history of the Baptist Mission to Nigeria, general books on Africa, and several Yoruba dictionaries.
    - Islam and Christianity: Ninety Questions and Answers, by Abd-Ul-Masih, 1965 (Box 16)
    - So This Is Africa, by Susan Anderson, 1946 (Box 16)
    - On the Trail of Livingston, by W.H. Anderson, 1919 (Box 16)
    - Moon of Africa, by Mrs. A. Bamijoko, undated (Box 16)
    - The Poor Christ of Bomba, by Mongo Beti, 1971 (Box 16)
    - Central Africa: Adventures and Missionary Labors, by T.J. Bowen, 1857 (Box 16)
    - Planting the Redeemer's Standard, by Edgar Burks, 1994, 2 copies (Box 16)
    - Through African Eyes, ed. Leon Clark, 1973 (Box 16)
    - The Baptist Mission of Nigeria, 1850-1993, by Travis Collins, 1993, 2 copies (Box 16)
    - Sunburnt Africa, by Kent Cottrell, undated (Box 17)
    - The Selfless Rabbi, by Deacon Ojo Fadelu, undated (Box 17)
    - Lokotown, by Cyprian Ekwensi, 1970 (Box 17)
    - How to Be a Nigerian, by Peter Enahoro, 1972, 2 copies (Box 17)
    - An Outline of Nigerian History, by M.C. English, 1959 (Box 17)
    - Nuer Religion, by E.E. Evans-Pritchard, undated (Box 17)
    - The Wimpy Harper Story, by Jesse Fletcher, 1966 (Box 17)
    - Memorials of Anna Hinderer, by Anna Hinderer, 1873 (Box 17)
    - Beyond the River Bend, by Heinrich Görtz, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Conversations with Ogotemmêli, by Marcel Griaule, 1970 (Box 17)
    - Traditional African Environments, by Toyin Huntar, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Taiwo Ati Kehinde, by Iwe Kini, 1948 (Box 17)
    - The History of the Yorubas, by O. Johnson, 1937, 2 copies (Box 18)
    - Basil Lee Lockett, by Elkin Lightfoot Lockett, 1936 (Box 18)
    - The Religion of the Yorubas, by J. Olumide Lucas, 1948 (Box 18)
    - Day Dawn in Yoruba Land, by Charles Maddry, 1939 (Box 18)
    - The Trial of Christopher Okigbo, by Ali A. Mazrui, 1971 (Box 18)
    - Along the African Path, by Dorothy McConnell, 1952 (Box 18)
    - Memoirs of Nigerian Days, by Mary McCormick, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Modern Poetry from Africa, eds. Gerald Moore and Ulli Beier, 1963 (Box 18)
    - Missionary Family Album, eds. Marjorie E. Moore and Inez Tuggle, 1948 (Box 18)
    - Ikale: Culture and Traditions, Oba Alayeluwa George Babatunde Faduyile-Adegun, 2008 undated (Box 18)
    - Life Principles: Lessons from the Lives of Abraham and Joseph, by S.A.K. Olaleye, 2008 (Box 18)
    - The Pathway to Purposeful Life, by S.A.K. Olaleye, undated (Box 18)
    - Continent in Commotion,by Ira N. Patterson, 1957, 2 copies (Box 19)
    - African Religions, by Benjamin C. Ray, 1976 (Box 19)
    - A Century in Nigeria, by George W. Sadler, 1950 (Box 19)
    - In the Shadow of the Sacred Grove, by Carol Spindel, 1989 (Box 19)
    - Nigerian Hairstyles, by Susie, undated (Box 19)
    - Between Niger and Nile, by Arnold Toynbee, 1965 (Box 19)
    - An Assessment of Reentry Issues of the Children of Missionaries, by Doris L. Walters, 1991 (Box 19)
    - Builders of a New Africa, by Nan Weeks, 1944 (Box 19)
    - Bible, in Yoruba, 1943 (Box 19)
    - The Broadman Hymnal, by 1940 (Box 19)
    - A Dictionary of the Yoruba Language, 1950 (Box 19)
    - Teach Yourself Yoruba, 1969 (Box 19)
    - Evangel Bells, by undated (Box 20)
    - Iwe Orin Ti Ijo Baptist Ni Nigeria, 3 copies (Box 20)
    - The Koran, undated (Box 20)
    - Longmans' Yoruba Series: Reader One, 1944 (Box 20)
    - The Round-Up, Baylor Yearbook, 1941-1942 (Box 20)
    - Masterlife I, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Masterlife II, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Tropical Africa, 1966 (Box 21)
    - Various pamphlet publications, 1972-1992 and undated, 8 items (Box 21)
  - Other Authors
    Includes diaries of Nigerian missionaries, books about African missionaries and about life in Africa.
    - This Is my Father's World, by Margaret T. Applegarth, 1947 (Box 22)
    - Hausa-English Dictionary, by Babbaa Ju-Gora ga Turanci, 1965 undated (Box 22)
    - The Baptist Mission of Nigeria, by Travis Collins, 1993 (Box 22)
    - More Than a Song, by James Draper, 1970 (Box 22)
    - Throw Momma From the Brain, arranged by Dave Hill, undated (Box 22)
    - Tullock Memoirs, by Helen Tullock, 1975-1976 (Box 22)
    - The Diaries of T. Keith Edwards, M.D., written in Africa from 1957-1968, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Brighter Grammar, by P.A. Ogundipe, 1983 (Box 22)
    - Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow: Devotional Messages, by Dr. I.N. Patterson, 1964 (Box 22)
      Electronic records consist of 2 document files (MS Word format) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.0002 gigabytes.
    - The Romance of Missions in Nigeria, by Samuel George Pinnock, 1917 (Box 22)
    - Handbook for Nigerian Mothers, by Carmella Schnautz, 1967 (Box 22)
    - The Peoples of Nigeria, by E. Spicer, 1962 (Box 22)
    - Baptist Work in Igede Ekiti, 2001 (Box 22)
    - Directory, The Southern Baptist Theological Seminary, 1965 (Box 22)
    - Good News: Easy Reading Book B-1 (Box 22)
    - This Is Your Life, 1971 (Box 22)
    - When we were young in Africa, by Polsgrove, undated (Box 35)
    - Lines Fallen in Pleasant Places, by Louise Hill, undated (Box 35)
    - Various digitized printed materials, books, and pamphlets, 0.02 Gigabytes
      Electronic records consist of 64 image files (JPEG format) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.02 gigabytes.
    - "A Handbook for Missionaries of the African Mission of the Foreign Mission Board of the Southern Baptist Convention" digitized selections, 1948; 1957
      Electronic records consist of 20 image files (JPEG format) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.004 gigabytes.
  - Baptist Mission to Nigeria Minutes
    - Minutes of the Baptist Mission Nigeria (photocopies), 1850-1940 (Box 35)
      Electronic record consists of 1 PDF document file extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.04 gigabytes.
    - Minutes of the Baptist Mission Nigeria (photocopies), 1903-1942 (Box 35)
      Electronic record consists of 1 PDF document file extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.03 gigabytes.
    - Minutes of the Baptist Mission Nigeria (photocopies), 1938-1943 (Box 35)
      Electronic record consists of 1 PDF document file extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.07 gigabytes.
    - Minutes of the Baptist Mission Nigeria (photocopies), 1953-1956 (Box 35)
      Electronic record consists of 1 PDF document file extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.02 gigabytes.
    - Minutes of the Baptist Mission Nigeria digital files, 1959-1998
      Electronic records consist of 38 document files (PDF format) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.18 gigabytes.
    - Roberson Collection "Index", 1984 (Box 35)
      Electronic record consists of 1 PDF document file extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.01 gigabytes.
- Visual Materials, 1941-1998 and undated, 9 boxes
  This series is divided into four subseries: slides, photo albums, mounted photographs, and foam-core mounted photographs.
  - Slides
    The slides subseries is chiefly composed of hundreds of slides from the McGee family's time in Nigeria. The slides are all numbered and grouped into several major categories (listed below). A description of each picture can be found in the Collection Information Series. Newer additions have been placed at the back of each major category.
    Slides 000-999: Missionaries and Missionary Kids ("MKs")
    Slides 1000-1999: Nigerians
    Slides 2000-2999: Baptist Mission Churches
    Slides 3000-3999: Baptist Mission Schools
    Slides 4000-4999: Baptist Mission Medical Work
    Slides 5000-5999: General Life Scenes
    Slides 6000-7999: Places/Locations
    Slides 8000-8999: Mission Stations
    Slides 9001-9999: Family/Personal
    - Slides 100s-200s (Box 24)
      Electronic records consist of 115 image files (JPEG and TIFF formats) and 2 HTML files extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.17 gigabytes.
    - Slides 300s (Box 24)
    - Slides 400s, 500s, 1000s (Box 24)
    - Slides 1100s, 1200s, 1300s, 2000s, 2100s (Box 24)
      Electronic records consist of 41 image files (JPEG and TIFF formats) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.12 gigabytes.
    - Slides 2200s-2300s (Box 24)
      Electronic records consist of 70 image files (JPEG and TIFF formats) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.26 gigabytes.
    - Slides 3000s (Box 24)
      Electronic records consist of 21 image files (JPEG and TIFF formats) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.14 gigabytes.
    - Slides 4000s (Box 24)
      Electronic records consist of 2 image files (JPEG format) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.0002 gigabytes.
    - Slides 5000s (Box 25)
      Electronic records consist of 14 image files (JPEG format) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.001 gigabytes.
    - Slides 6000s (Box 25)
      Electronic records consist of 25 image files (JPEG and TIFF formats) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.08 gigabytes.
    - Slides 8000s, 2 folders (Box 25)
      Electronic records consist of 143 image files (JPEG and TIFF formats) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.23 gigabytes.
    - Slides 9000s (Box 25)
      Electronic records consist of 383 image files (JPEG, TIFF, and PSD formats) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.63 gigabytes.
  - Photo albums
    The photo albums include pictures of John S. and Doris McGee's early life in college, in seminary and in early Nigeria, John David's baby years, a missionary trip to Brazil, and other family pictures.
    - Old album, probably from Doris McGee's side of the family (Box 26)
    - John David McGee's baby book (Box 26)
    - Doris and John S. McGee's college, seminary and early Nigeria (Box 26)
    - Doris McGee's college and seminary years (Box 27)
    - John S. and Doris McGee's send-offs, 1977 (Box 27)
    - John S. and Doris McGee's Foreign Mission Board retirement service, 1978 (Box 27)
    - Mission trip to Brazil, 1980s (Box 28)
    - From Doris McGee to John S. McGee and children for Christmas, 1990s (Box 29)
  - Mounted Photographs
    Seven 16x20 mounted color prints furnished by Foreign Mission Board in various missionary camps in Nigeria and photographed by Gerald S. Harvey. Captions are original.
    - Joinkrama: literacy class, with pastor teaching children outside (Box 30)
    - Ikogosi: Nigerian Baptist Youth Camp, devotions; with John S. McGee leading (Box 30)
    - Kontagora: grass church, outdoor service; pastor preaching to members and Mrs. L. Gene Legg, missionary (Box 30)
    - Igede: Araromi Baptist Church, building, sign; Missionary John B. Hill with men (Box 30)
    - Ogbomosho: Baptist Health Service, Lockett Memorial Baptist Church; people leaving worship service, building in the background (Box 30)
    - Ogbomosho: Western Nigerian Blind Training Farm, devotional; Mrs. David N. Mayhall, missionary, playing accordion (Box 30)
    - Ogbomosho: Baptist Hospital, building; missionary Valda Long, R.N., in front with people, sign at right (Box 30)
  - Foam-core mounted photographs
    Includes memorial photos of John S. and Doris McGee, early photos, John S. and Doris McGee with their grand- and great-grandchildren and the last photographs before John S. and Doris' deaths.
    - Rev. John S. McGee memorial photo, 11x17.5 (Box 31)
    - Doris T. McGee memorial photo, 11x17.5 (Box 31)
    - Doris T. McGee, around college years, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris McGee wedding photo, 1941, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - McGee family in Nigeria, 1950-1951, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - Doris T. McGee with great-grandson, Angus, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - Doris T. McGee with great-granddaughter, Se Ferrel, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris McGee with granddaughter, Erin McGee Ferrell, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - McGee's at Erin's graduation, Mount Holyoke College, 1994, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris McGee at Ft. Lauderdale; last Christmas together, 1997, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris McGee, Christmas, 1997, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris McGee, last photograph together, 1998, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris McGee, last (close-up) photograph, 1998, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris and Erin McGee on porch swing, early 1990s, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris McGee, Christmas, 1997, 8x10 (Box 32)
    - John S. and Doris McGee, Fruitland, early 1990s, 8x10 (Box 32)
  - Unclassified digital images, 0.01 Gigabytes
    Electronic records consist of 26 image files (JPEG and TIFF formats) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.01 gigabytes.
- Audiovisual Materials, 1945-2009 and undated, 3 boxes
  The Audio-Visual Materials Series includes several recordings and films taken by the McGee family members of various tours in Nigeria. The films range from 1945 to 2009, and span the three generations of McGee missionaries. Also included is a DVD about the Conferment of Chieftaincy on John David McGee. The audio materials include several recordings of John and Doris McGee telling their life stories, talking about missionary work in Nigeria (especially regarding Baptist churches), and their first tour. The reel-to-reel tapes include audio-recordings of the McGee family as they were separated during various Nigerian tours. Ten super-8 film reels document John David McGee's trips to Nigeria from 1972 to 1983, which were the video source for the DVDs and video-cassette tapes.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  This series may contain original audiovisual materials which are closed to patron use. Some use copies are available in the collection. Otherwise, Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
  Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
  - Old Nigerian Film, 1945-1957
    Scope and Contents
    16mm compilation reel, created John S. McGee and documenting his family's Baptist mission work in Nigeria in the 1940s and 1950s.
    - 16mm original (Box 33, Film-reel RL10042-F16-0001)
    - Digital preservation and use copies, including a version narrated by the McGees and description notes by John David McGee. (Digital-materials SET-0001)
  - DVD: Nigeria: 1972; DVD: Old Nigeria: 1945-1957 (with narration by the McGees) (Box 33)
  - VHS: McGee and Schmidt's trip to Nigeria (summer of 1971) - edited for VCR in 1990 (Master Copy) (Box 33)
  - VHS: Nigerian Films: from 16mm movies by John S. McGee during 1945-1953 - transferred to VHS in 1991 (Box 33)
  - DVD: Visitation and Conferment of Chieftaincy of Mr. and Mrs. John David McGee, 2009; DVD: McGee Nigeria Footage, July 2009 (Box 33)
  - CDs, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Old Nigeria (Box 33)
    - Nigeria (Box 33)
    - Igede Fairwell (Box 33)
    - JS McGee Final Sermon (Box 33)
      Electronic records consist of 1 document files (MS Word format) extracted from USB thumb drive, approximately 0.003 gigabytes.
    - JS McGee Life Story, 6 CDs (Box 33)
    - Doris McGee, 3 CDs (Box 33)
    - First Tour, 4 CDs (Box 33)
    - Churches, 4 CDs (Box 33)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes (Box 34)
    - McGees to John David, 1963, 10 tapes (Box 34)
    - Possibly John David to parents, 1963-1964 (Box 34)
    - McGees to John David, possibly from Oshogbo, 1963 (Box 34)
    - Sidney to John David, possibly from Oshogbo, 1963 (Box 34)
    - John David to parents, from Mars Hill College, circa 1964 (Box 34)
    - John David to Gail Thompson, circa 1964, 5 tapes (Box 34)
    - Sidney to John David (?), from Newton School, circa 1964 (Box 34)
    - McGees to Humphreys (?), circa 1964 (Box 34)
    - Sidney to McGees, from Louisville, circa 1964 (Box 34)
    - McGees to John David, 2 tapes (Box 34)
    - Uncertain persons and date, circa 1968 (?) (Box 34)
    - Dr. I.N. Patterson, circa 1964 (?) (Box 34)
    - Dr. J.T. Ayorinde, circa 1964 (?) (Box 34)
    - From McGees, 1964 (?) (Box 34)
    - Sidney to John David (?), circa 1964 (?) (Box 34)
  - Super-8 Film
    - Ten reels documenting John David McGee's trips to Nigeria from 1972 to 1983 (Box 23)
  - Audio cassette tapes
    Talking letters and other recordings from the McGees in Nigeria and Seattle. Supplemental information provided by John David McGee.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services in advance to request the production of listening copies.
    - Notes on tapes, 2016 (Box 35)
    - Tapes A-E, 1-35, 1972-1977; 42 audiocassettes (Box 36)
    - Tapes 36-75A, 1972-1977; 42 audiocassettes (Box 37)
    - Tapes 76-117, 1972-1977; 42 audiocassettes (Box 38)
    - Tapes 118-144, 1972-1977; 42 audiocassettes (Box 39)
    - Tapes 145-168; S-190-S-207, 1972-1977; 1981-1982; 42 audiocassettes (Box 40)
    - Tapes S-208-S-249, 1982-1983; 42 audiocassettes (Box 41)
    - Tapes S-250-S-260, M-261-M-265, 1984-1991; 16 audiocassettes (Box 42)